<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: javascript, | Maciej Kus is not a Figure Skater]]></title>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/categories/javascript/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-15T09:26:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://maciejkus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maciej Kus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[canvas-game]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/03/14/canvas-game/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T10:03:59-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/03/14/canvas-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to try out Jasmine, which is a JavaScript unit testing library. I also had an idea for what could be a fun little <a href='http://maciejkus.com/canvas-game/'>game</a>, so I went ahead and made a html5/canvas game and used Jasmine to test things as I coded.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Though there are some plug-ins out there to make Jasmine work with canvas rendering, I skipped those, so I didn&rsquo;t truly test everything. But I did test all the non-drawing aspects of the game.</p>

<p>The game is simple enough that I don&rsquo;t think the unit testing helped too much, but if I were to expand the game it is useful to have the existing tests in place.</p>

<p>The tricky thing about this game was all the math. Do you remember those smart aleck kids in math class who would ask the teacher when they would ever use the math that they were learning? Well, at times I felt like my work on this game justified as an answer for all those teachers. This might have been the first time I ever had to find the intersection of two line segments outside of a school setting.</p>

<p>The game is all vanilla JavaScript using the HTML5 canvas object. Play it <a href='http://maciejkus.com/canvas-game/'>here</a>. The source code is on <a href='https://github.com/MaciejKus/canvas-fly-game'>github</a>. I am now familiar enough with Jasmine that I can and will use unit testing for future projects. Wins all around.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roman numbers]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/02/12/roman-numbers/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-12T16:07:50-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/02/12/roman-numbers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A quick <a href='http://maciejkus.com/roman-numeral-calculator/'>Roman numeral converter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[using-d3-to-visualize-data]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/01/19/using-d3-to-visualize-data/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-19T14:10:57-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/01/19/using-d3-to-visualize-data</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started playing with d3.js, a visualization library. I got some data from the kickfurther website using a little python script I wrote. The script parsed out the relevant data and saved it as a JavaScript object.</p>

<p>From there I used <a href='http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1230000000345'>Interactive Data Visualization for the Web</a> as an intro to d3.js and built a fun little bubble graph. I don&rsquo;t know if a bubble graph is the most informative way to present this data, but it was the coolest looking, and mainly I was attempting to learn d3.js.</p>

<p>Check out my <a href='http://maciejkus.com/kickfurther-data/'>Kickfurther visualization</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Breakout Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/11/22/another-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-22T16:06:56-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/11/22/another-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welp, I made another breakout game. This time with Phaser.js. It was my first project with Phaser and was a nice introduction to the game engine.</p>

<p>Play <a href='http://maciejkus.com/border-breakout/'>Border Breakout</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[pizza calculator]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/11/15/pizza-calculator/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-15T15:18:20-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/11/15/pizza-calculator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>See input the diameter and cost of different pizza&rsquo;s and see which is the best deal. <a href='http://maciejkus.com/pizza_calc/'>Pizza calculator</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
