<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: javascript, | Maciej Kus is not a Figure Skater]]></title>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/categories/javascript/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-19T15:54:38-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://maciejkus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maciej Kus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[using-d3-to-visualize-data]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/01/19/using-d3-to-visualize-data/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-19T14:10:57-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/01/19/using-d3-to-visualize-data</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started playing with d3.js, a visualization library. I got some data from the kickfurther website using a little python script I wrote. The script parsed out the relevant data and saved it as a JavaScript object.</p>

<p>From there I used <a href='http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1230000000345'>Interactive Data Visualization for the Web</a> as an intro to d3.js and built a fun little bubble graph. I don&rsquo;t know if a bubble graph is the most informative way to present this data, but it was the coolest looking, and mainly I was attempting to learn d3.js.</p>

<p>Check out my <a href='http://maciejkus.com/kickfurther-data/'>Kickfurther visualization</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Breakout Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/11/22/another-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-22T16:06:56-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/11/22/another-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welp, I made another breakout game. This time with Phaser.js. It was my first project with Phaser and was a nice introduction to the game engine.</p>

<p>Play <a href='http://maciejkus.com/border-breakout/'>Border Breakout</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[pizza calculator]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/11/15/pizza-calculator/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-15T15:18:20-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/11/15/pizza-calculator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>See input the diameter and cost of different pizza&rsquo;s and see which is the best deal. <a href='http://maciejkus.com/pizza_calc/'>Pizza calculator</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canvas Match 3 Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/09/29/canvas-match-3-game/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-29T09:39:45-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/09/29/canvas-match-3-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to make a match three game as a first step to learning a new game engine. Since Enchant.js is pretty much abandoned at this point, I figured it was time to try something new, and I decided on Phaser.js. So I start making the game, but it just seems that using a game engine was overkill for something as simple as a match-three game.</p>

<p>So I decided to save learning Phaser.js for a different project and just make the match-three game using plain old vanilla JavaScript and the html5 canvas element. Play it <a href='http://brogress.smoothiegains.com/smoothie_match/'>here</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The coolest thing about making the game was dealing with all the animations. I split up the animations to only render the tile which is moving, instead of rendering the whole canvas every time something has to be changed. This saves a lot of resources, making the game run faster and smoother. The trick was to make sure that things didn&rsquo;t overlap.  The animations run asynchronously, so I had to avoid situations where multiple animations were running on top of one another, or that the logic from a running animation did not interfere with the logic of a new mouse click.</p>

<p>The game is pretty basic, but I was able to remove all the little glitches I came across when testing. I&rsquo;m also pleased to have made a game where the graphics actually look OK. This is all thanks to finding creative commons images and playing with GIMP a little bit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[jsbreakouts]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/08/11/jsbreakouts/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-11T09:12:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/08/11/jsbreakouts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a project, JavaScript <a href="http://www.jsbreakouts.org/">Breakouts</a> which is a collection of different JavaScript game engines. All the game engines are used to create the same version of Breakout, with the same features, etc. It&rsquo;s a way to allow people to compare different game engines by looking at them in action.</p>

<p>Since I&rsquo;ve used enchant.js before, I figured I would add an enchant.js version to the Breakouts. The game can be played <a href="http://www.jsbreakouts.org/enchantjs/index.html">here</a>. Coding this game I realized that enchant.js is out of date. The last time it has been updated was around 2013. There was one <a href="https://github.com/wise9/enchant.js/issues/312">issue</a> where I actually had to go in and change the code for enchant.js to make the game work. There is an outdated web audio line:</p>

<p><code>this.src.disconnect(this.connectTarget);</code></p>

<p>This caused Chrome and other webkit based browsers to issue a</p>

<p><code>Uncaught InvalidAccessError: Failed to execute 'disconnect' on 'AudioNode': the given destination is not connected.</code></p>

<p>error. This was fixed by changing the above line to</p>

<p><code>this.src.disconnect();</code></p>

<p>Before this change, the game would crash as soon as a sound was played. I see there are other issues with enchant.js. On older versions of Firefox the game does not finish loading. Instead it throws a</p>

<p><code>Error: failed in Deferred</code></p>

<p>error. It&rsquo;s unfortunate, but it seems like enchant.js is no longer being maintained, and so I will have to find a new game engine to use, if I ever decide to use a game engine for a game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
