<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: jquery, | Maciej Kus -- Bay Area JavaScript Developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/categories/jquery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-17T17:49:38-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://maciejkus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maciej Kus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[jumpy jquery slide animation]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/10/11/jumpy-jquery-slide-animation/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-11T13:00:21-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/10/11/jumpy-jquery-slide-animation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>CSS uses collapsing margins. What this means is that when two objects both have a margin value which overlaps, the margins are combines. So say you have two buttons, both of which have margin: 24px;.</p>

<p>Rather than creating a space of 48px between the two, CSS combines or collapses the margins into one value of 24px.</p>

<p>This is fine most of the time, but is a long known issue with jQuery animations. Here&rsquo;s a 5 year old post describing it:
<a href="http://bugs.jquery.com/ticket/7442">http://bugs.jquery.com/ticket/7442</a></p>

<p>Basically jQuery animations become jumpy when margins are combined. I haven&rsquo;t looked too in-depth into the jQuery code to see exactly how animations like .slide() work, but the collapsing margins are the reason for the jumpiness.</p>

<p>The solution is simply to remove any overlapping margins in the element which is being animated, along with any bordering elements. Istead of having two buttons both of which have a margin value of 24px (but combined CSS still only created a 24px margin between the two) have one of the buttons have a 0px margin and the other a 24px margin. The space between them will still be the same, and now jQuery animations looks smooth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[wage-calc]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/09/05/wage-calc/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-05T17:18:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/09/05/wage-calc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A <a href='http://maciejkus.com/wage-calculator/'>wage calculator</a> which calculates inflation, top CEO compensation, S&amp;P 500, and San Francisco real estate growth. See if r is greater than g in the short term.</p>

<p>The chart was made using chart.js</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
