<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: angularjs, | Maciej Kus is not a Figure Skater]]></title>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/categories/angularjs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-23T09:53:15-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://maciejkus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maciej Kus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Searchable-Reddit-Brogress]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/09/06/searchable-reddit-brogress/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-06T11:16:17-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/09/06/searchable-reddit-brogress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reddit has a number of fitness progress picture communities. The problem is there is no good way to search through the posts. A lot of the posts are either people trying to lose weight, or 16 year olds who gain 30 pounds of muscle in 3 months. I am not interested in losing weight, nor do I have the raging growth hormones of a teenager.</p>

<p>I wanted to be able to search through the posts to find photos of people similar to me in height and weight so I could have a realistic fitness goal to strive for when I go to the gym. So, using angularJS I made my own.</p>

<p>I present the world with a <a href='http://brogress.smoothiegains.com/'>searchable fitness photo</a> web app.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[angular_forum]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/06/22/angular-forum/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-22T14:46:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/06/22/angular-forum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welp, I made a simple forum using angularJS. This is a lot more of what angular was meant to do than that baseball game I made a bit ago. It&rsquo;s a simple single page app. I did not create any backend functionality to save the posts or anything like that, partly because it is just an exercise, and partly because github   pages do not have backend access.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>You can see it at <a href="http://maciejkus.com/angular-forum/">http://maciejkus.com/angular-forum/</a>
You can make new posts, you can click on a username to see post titles made by that user. Nothing too fancy but it covers a lot of angular ideas.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[angular-baseball-game]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/06/05/angular-baseball-game/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-05T12:40:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/06/05/angular-baseball-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by a Codewars kata I created a simple <a href="http://maciejkus.com/baseball-game/">baseball game</a>. It was the first time I used AngularJS, but I feel like the Angular was unnecessary. I will need to build a few other pages to get the full idea of Angular.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
