<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: enchantjs, | Maciej Kus -- Bay Area JavaScript Developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/categories/enchantjs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-10T18:33:54-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://maciejkus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maciej Kus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[jsbreakouts]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/08/11/jsbreakouts/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-11T09:12:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/08/11/jsbreakouts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a project, JavaScript <a href="http://www.jsbreakouts.org/">Breakouts</a> which is a collection of different JavaScript game engines. All the game engines are used to create the same version of Breakout, with the same features, etc. It&rsquo;s a way to allow people to compare different game engines by looking at them in action.</p>

<p>Since I&rsquo;ve used enchant.js before, I figured I would add an enchant.js version to the Breakouts. The game can be played <a href="http://www.jsbreakouts.org/enchantjs/index.html">here</a>. Coding this game I realized that enchant.js is out of date. The last time it has been updated was around 2013. There was one <a href="https://github.com/wise9/enchant.js/issues/312">issue</a> where I actually had to go in and change the code for enchant.js to make the game work. There is an outdated web audio line:</p>

<p><code>this.src.disconnect(this.connectTarget);</code></p>

<p>This caused Chrome and other webkit based browsers to issue a</p>

<p><code>Uncaught InvalidAccessError: Failed to execute 'disconnect' on 'AudioNode': the given destination is not connected.</code></p>

<p>error. This was fixed by changing the above line to</p>

<p><code>this.src.disconnect();</code></p>

<p>Before this change, the game would crash as soon as a sound was played. I see there are other issues with enchant.js. On older versions of Firefox the game does not finish loading. Instead it throws a</p>

<p><code>Error: failed in Deferred</code></p>

<p>error. It&rsquo;s unfortunate, but it seems like enchant.js is no longer being maintained, and so I will have to find a new game engine to use, if I ever decide to use a game engine for a game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
