<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: design | Maciej Kus -- Bay Area JavaScript Developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-20T10:36:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://maciejkus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maciej Kus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[design first]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/02/16/design-first/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-16T09:37:13-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2016/02/16/design-first</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When making a game, or probably any program it is probably a better idea to design what you want to create before you actually begin to code.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I started working on a little RPG style game recently, but I started to code before I had a full idea of how the game will be played, what the goals of the game will be, etc. I figured that this would all come along as I coded. It&rsquo;s happened before with other things I wrote. But this time I just kept running into road blocks. I would either have too many ideas and now know how to implement them all to interact with one another or I just didn&rsquo;t know where to go from a certain idea and how that idea would further the gameplay.</p>

<p>It wasn&rsquo;t a coding issue. It was that I was trying to make something that I didn&rsquo;t have a clear concept of. I have heard that writers of novels will find that their characters end up doing things that the author never expected while writing the book. I had hopes that the game would do the same.</p>

<p>It did not.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m putting the game &lsquo;on hold&rsquo; for now because I just cannot figure out what I want the actual gameplay to be like. But it was a valuable lesson. Have a design before actually starting to code. At least a rough one that can change along the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
