<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: games | Maciej Kus -- Bay Area JavaScript Developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/categories/games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maciejkus.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-19T14:41:24-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://maciejkus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maciej Kus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[jsbreakouts]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/08/11/jsbreakouts/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-11T09:12:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/08/11/jsbreakouts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a project, JavaScript <a href="http://www.jsbreakouts.org/">Breakouts</a> which is a collection of different JavaScript game engines. All the game engines are used to create the same version of Breakout, with the same features, etc. It&rsquo;s a way to allow people to compare different game engines by looking at them in action.</p>

<p>Since I&rsquo;ve used enchant.js before, I figured I would add an enchant.js version to the Breakouts. The game can be played <a href="http://www.jsbreakouts.org/enchantjs/index.html">here</a>. Coding this game I realized that enchant.js is out of date. The last time it has been updated was around 2013. There was one <a href="https://github.com/wise9/enchant.js/issues/312">issue</a> where I actually had to go in and change the code for enchant.js to make the game work. There is an outdated web audio line:</p>

<p><code>this.src.disconnect(this.connectTarget);</code></p>

<p>This caused Chrome and other webkit based browsers to issue a</p>

<p><code>Uncaught InvalidAccessError: Failed to execute 'disconnect' on 'AudioNode': the given destination is not connected.</code></p>

<p>error. This was fixed by changing the above line to</p>

<p><code>this.src.disconnect();</code></p>

<p>Before this change, the game would crash as soon as a sound was played. I see there are other issues with enchant.js. On older versions of Firefox the game does not finish loading. Instead it throws a</p>

<p><code>Error: failed in Deferred</code></p>

<p>error. It&rsquo;s unfortunate, but it seems like enchant.js is no longer being maintained, and so I will have to find a new game engine to use, if I ever decide to use a game engine for a game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canvas/HTML5 Tower Defense]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/07/06/canvas-tower-defense/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-06T17:30:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/07/06/canvas-tower-defense</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I made a fairly simply tower defense game in html5/canvas/javascript. It works fine as is. Most of the features I would want to create are there, the game just needs some work on the actual game play. Details like the cost of towers, and how rapid the attackers are spawned will probably need to be changed to make the game more enjoyable. The current version works well enough to play.</p>

<p>Check it out at <a href="http://maciejkus.com/tower/">http://maciejkus.com/tower/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[angular-baseball-game]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/06/05/angular-baseball-game/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-05T12:40:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2015/06/05/angular-baseball-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by a Codewars kata I created a simple <a href="http://maciejkus.com/baseball-game/">baseball game</a>. It was the first time I used AngularJS, but I feel like the Angular was unnecessary. I will need to build a few other pages to get the full idea of Angular.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple HTML5 Games]]></title>
    <link href="http://maciejkus.com/blog/2014/08/04/simple-html5-games/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T10:39:21-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://maciejkus.com/blog/2014/08/04/simple-html5-games</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
A while ago I wanted to work with graphics. Before then all I have ever coded were text based programs. Calculators, problem generators, text games, console scripts, etc. I figured a game would be the best way to do this and that HTML5/canvas would be the best area to learn. Internet browsers have largely adopted canvas and it works on all kinds of devices, including smart phones. I hope posting these early experiments will allow others to speed up their own learning of HTML5/canvas. 
</p>


<p>A coworker suggested I start with making a breakout style game and then move on to pong. My first step was to actually learn how to draw a <a href='../../../../../html5-games/ball_shadow.html'>circle</a>. Then how to move the circle. Once I got that down the rest was easy.
</p>


<!-- more -->


<p>OK, maybe not easy, but there is enough documentation out there that I was able to make  some simple graphical programs. Rather than dive right into breakout I made a little 'game' where balls simply bounce around in two 'rooms'. This was largely a way to practice collision detection and collision response before making a more advanced game. The result can be played <a href='../../../../../html5-games/click-balls.html'>here</a>. The collision response in the game is definitely lacking, but it worked well enough for me to feel like I understood how things should work.
</p>


<p>
After that I felt like I understood collisions well enough that I did not need to make a breakout game and instead could move straight to a pong game, which is what I did. Instead of regular pong I made it more of a wall-ball style game where both players are on the same side. It's pretty much pong, with a tiny difference. See it in action <a href='../../../../../html5-games/wallball.html'>here</a>.
</p>


<p>
Finally, I wanted something more advanced, so I made a space shooter game. Instead of trying to use sprites I just used basic canvas shapes like circles, but the idea works pretty well. Play it <a href='../../../../../html5-games/shooter.html'>here</a>.
</p>


<p>
The above three were all learning experiences, and I believe I could go through the code and make it a bit nicer and maybe more efficient today. I am posting them as I originally wrote them. No improvments or anything, but I found that looking at how other simple games were coded was very helpful. Hopefully looking at the page source for the above might be helpful for others who are starting out. 
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
